Jonathan Barceló Iñiguez

Product Human

+1 469 274 1619

barcelo.jonathan@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonabar/

https://github.com/jonabari/

I'm an agile project manager with experience in web and game development, audiovisual content production, and localization. Having developed a diverse skillset through collaborations with peers across the world, my goal is to grow as a technical PM for international and distributed teams.

Relevant Experience

Reality Crisis

We are remote mobile gaming start-up based out of Finland, currently working on our first release, the first truly Augmented Reality Skateboarding game. Learn more at: skatrix.io

2018 - present Consultant

Freelance

- **Thinkful:** I am an advisor for Thinkful's newly launched technical project management curriculum, which includes instructional design for lessons in waterfall and agile project management methodologies, as well as introductory level web development content for non-technical learners.
- **Trilogy Education Services (2U)**: As an Advisory Board Member, I introduced remote collaboration tools and methodologies to the curriculum development teams' workflows. I also contributed content for the company's user experience, data storytelling, and full stack development curricula.
- Fotosíntesis Media: An independent animation studio from Mexico Cit, where I've led story revisions and creative development for: A Costume for Nicolas (2020) Beast (2021) Unannounced animated feature (2023)

2015 - 2018 **Producer**

Riot Games

I worked with internal and external teams to ship the first wave of original regional content. In my time in this role, our catalogue grew to include websites, marketing microsites, documentaries, Esports news and analysis content, behind the scenes features, animated shorts, and live audiovisual experiences.

2014 - 2015 Localization Coordinator

Riot Games

I designed and implemented best practices for the localization of audiovisual assets in the League of Legends catalog, web pages, graphics, comics, promos, and in-game VO. I was also in charge of managing LATAM localization Quality Assurance for League of Legends' two week patch cycle, and a collaborative approach to VO script localization that led to an increased positive sentiment in new champion VO reception.

2013 - 2015 Co-Founder, Design Researcher

MedicSana Inc.

MedicSana was an mHealth start-up company targeting underserved segments in growing economies. Read more at: https://bit.ly/2Zf3Jj4

Technical Web Translator

Rigaku

I used Drupal to manage the localization of Rigaku's full catalog of online promotional materials with a translating partner.

Education

2007 - 2011 The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Spanish Language and Literature

Bridging Disciplines: Film studies

Certificates

2019 Professional Scrum Master (PSM I), Scrum.org
2019 Full Stack Developer, Tecnológico de Monterrey

2017 *Certified Professional Agile Coach,* ICAgile

2016 Certified Professional Agile Project Manager, ICAgile